Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/liton-miah (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE)
Logging
Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

Languages

English

Certifications

Design Patterns
HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web
Developers
Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)

Service-Oriented Architecture

Java Programming: Principles of Software Design

Liton Miah

Principal Software Engineer at BJIT Dhaka, Bangladesh

Summary

A proficient and self-motivated web application developer with a strong technical background and over 9+ years of professional experience, who possesses self-discipline and the ability to work individually and with team. Able to play a key role throughout a web application development to ensure maximum accessibility, customer experience and usability with creating engaging creative solution in deadline and have the ability to produce detailed technical specifications for client requirements.

I like most to develop innovative idea and implement quite critical things.

Specially I always welcome to the new things.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

- Analysis project requirements, time costing, database design and SDLC prepare.
- Exhaustive knowledge of Java, Spring Boot, Spring/Hibernate, Groovy on Grails, JQgrid, Jasper Report and PostgreSQL etc.
- Comprehensive knowledge of PHP, MySQL, Codeigniter, Wordpress, Joomla, HTML5, CSS3,

Responsive Design, jQuery, Ajax, JavaScript, AngularJS, Angular CLI, twitter bootstrap and API etc.

- Creating websites and Web applications that are user-friendly, effective and appealing.
- Creating web services, web API's for various applications.
- Producing, modifying and maintaining websites and web applications.
- Testing a website, web application & identifying bugs & technical problems.

Experience

BJIT

Principal Software Engineer
March 2023 - Present (2 years 5 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Newgen Technology Limited Senior Software Engineer September 2021 - March 2023 (1 year 7 months) Dhaka, Bangladesh

BRAC IT Services Limited

6 years 8 months

Senior Software Engineer
July 2018 - September 2021 (3 years 3 months)

Road # 5, House # 115, Block - B, Niketan Society, Gulshan, Dhaka - 1212

Software Engineer

February 2015 - June 2018 (3 years 5 months)

Road # 5, House # 115, Block - B, Niketan Society, Gulshan, Dhaka - 1212

Writing Code in Java platform and Javascript, Writing SQL queries, Design and develop project module wise with Groovy on Grails framework and JQgrid also. And also design and develop report using Jasper iReport tool. Other than testing code, debugging, fixing functionalities, UI related issues, report issues on urgency and helping other team members. Also working on android application development and web service development.

CodeCloud Technology LTD.

Software Engineer

March 2014 - January 2015 (11 months)

12/A R.K. Mission Road, Motijheel, Dhaka-1203

Web Application Development Using PHP Codeigniter and CakePHP Framework, Database Analysis and Design, Website Analysis and Design, PSD to HTML Design and Responsive template design by Bootstrap. Other than testing code, debugging, fixing functionalities, UI related issues on clients need and helping other team members.

STM Software Limited
Junior programmer
June 2013 - February 2014 (9 months)

Sristy Tower (5th Floor), 1041/3, Begum Rokeya Sarani, Dhaka-1216, Bangladesh

Responsible for Website design and Development using Joomla, Wordpress and Opencart then Website Testing, Deploy and Fixing problems.

Education

United International University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science and Engineering · (2010 - 2014)

Bangladesh Institute of Information Technology(BIIT)

Diploma Engineering, Computer Engineering · (2006 - 2009)

Sonahata High School

S.S.C, Science · (2001 - 2005)